omgblog.com 2019-05-15

# OMG, it's our PRIVACY POLICY | OMG.BLOG

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://omg.blog.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available [here](https://automattic.com/privacy/). After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Email address and contact info

OMG.BLOG may ask you to register and provide information that personally identifies you, including when you register as a subscriber to receive e-mail newsletters or respond to a contest or marketing campaign. The information gathered is used to enhance the user experience on our site and to identify frequent visitors. Information collected will not be sold, distributed or otherwise disseminated to outside sources. We may use your personal information for two primary purposes:

»  To alert you to new published blog entries and updates to comment threads  
»  To coordinate the delivery of contest prizes

If you do not wish to receive such mailings, please let us know by clicking the “unsubscribe” link in the email or by contacting us at subscribe [at] omg [dot] blog. We will be sure your name is removed from our list.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select "Remember Me", your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

We use [Google Analytics](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and [Chartbeat](https://chartbeat.com/privacy/) to keep track of important information about our visitors. This includes but is not limited to: What website you came from to get here, how long you stay for, and what kind of computer you’re using. If you like, you can opt out of Google Analytics tracking [here](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

## Who we share your data with

We share visitor data with audience measurement firm [Quantcast](https://www.quantcast.com/privacy/) so that the value of our ad inventory is clear to potential advertisers, and with [NativeAI](https://native.ai/privacy) to inform us about the content preferences of our readers.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve the ads displayed on our website. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email or phone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please click [here](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

We collect information about visitors who comment for the Akismet anti-spam service, which typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).

## Disclaimers

OMG.BLOG is protected by federal copyright law and material published in print or online may not be reproduced in whole or part without the permission of the publishers. OMG.BLOG assumes no responsibility for unsolicited materials submitted for publication. OMG.BLOG is also not responsible for claims made by advertisers or materials provided by advertisers or their agents.

## Contact Us

If you have questions or comments regarding OMG.BLOG privacy practices, please write to publisher [at] omg [dot] blog.
